ADEWALE MUSILIU

AJMAN, UAE · +971581592994 +971563613624

Musiliu.adewale@yahoo.com · LinkedIn My Portfolio

I am an ambitious front-end developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various CSS and HTML options, plugins, development platforms and security requirements according to up-to-date standards. Data-driven individual with excellent grasp of Google Analytics and other search optimization needs.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - PRESENT

WEB DEVELOPER, FREELANCE

- Coded websites using HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, Sass and JavaScript.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Built a Drop shipping and Print-on-demand e-commerce store with Shopify.
- Developed user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages, including HTML,
 CSS and JAVASCRIPT.
- Developed web pages fetching API from third party web application.
- Familiarity with Node Package Manager.

2017 - 2020

SECURITY OFFICER, AL RAED COMPANY

- Guarded properties against theft and destruction.
- Routine access point inspections.
- Observed the surveillance footage.

EDUCATION

OCTOBER 2019

THE WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP, UDEMY

I enrolled in the highest rated web development bootcamp. It gave me the basic understanding of how the web works and fundamentals of HTML, CSS and JAVASCRIPT

SEPTEMBER 2015

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF ILORIN

Within 2011 to 2015 I was enrolled in the university and obtained bachelors in Geology and Mineral Sciences.

SKILLS

- CODE DEBUGGING
- HTML
- CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- UI IMPROVEMENT
- UX DESIGN
- GIT AND GITHUB
- BOOTSTRAP
- NODE PACKAGE MANAGER

ACTIVITIES

I am a self-taught web developer that enjoys learning and constant growth. Over the course of my learning I have created more than 30 repositories on github and also obtained Digital Marketing certification from Google. I have been working with the web at a really young age and by far it has been the most fulfilling thing to do for me. I have managed to put various blogsites together with WordPress and also Shopify e-commerce stores, but to build a web page from absolutely nothing has been fascinating. I am looking to keep improving and learn the latest and best technology out there.